A Guide to the David Schwab Collection of T.S. Eliot Manuscripts 1918-1933
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
David Schwab Collection of T.S. Eliot Manuscripts 1918-1933
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
7556
20 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Contents List
- Burbank with a Baedeker: Bleistein with a Cigar ca. 1919, TMs, 1 page
  with autograph printer's marks
- Gerontion ca. 1919, TMs, 2 p.
  with autograph corrections and with autograph printer's marks
- Correspondence
- T.S. Eliot to John Rodker 1918 November 7, ALS, 2 p.
  with typed copy, n.d., of the original
- T.S. Eliot to John Rodker 1918 December 2, APC, initialled, 1 p.
  with typed copy,n.d., of the original
- T.S. Eliot to John Rodker 1919 May 17, TLS, 1 p.
  When sent to Rodker, the letter included manuscripts of Eliot's Burbank with a Baedeker: Bleistein with a Cigar, Ode, and Sweeney Erect. The manuscripts are not present. Burbank with a Baedeker: Bleistein with a Cigar, (see above) was acquired separately by Schwab.
- T.S. Eliot to John Rodker 1919 May 21, ALS, 1 p.
- T.S. Eliot to John Rodker 1919 June 1, ALS, 3 p.
- T.S. Eliot to John Rodker 1919 July 9, ALS, 1 p.
- T.S. Eliot to John Rodker ca. late 1919 to early 1920, AL initialled, 2 p.
- T.S. Eliot to John Rodker 1920 February 6, ALS, 1 p.
- 1922 February 5, ALS, 2 p.
- T.S. Eliot to John Rodker 1922 July 10, TLS, 1 p.
- I.P. Fassett (secretary to T.S. Eliot) to David Schwab 1926 July 8, TLS, 1 p.
- William E. Hughes (of Lloyd's Bank Ltd.) to Clarence R. De Sola 1926 July 12, TLS, 1 p.
- T.S. Eliot to Clarence R. De Sola 1927 July 26, TLS, 1 p.
- Olga H. Pavlow (of Brewer, Warren & Putnam) to David Schwab 1931 October 17, TLS, 1 p.
  with envelope
- Miscellaneous
- Autograph and typewritten copies of portions of Eliot's critical works, autograph and typewritten copies, 49 p.
- Autograph and typewritten portions of draft of, and notes for, projected book on Eliot by David Schwab, Autographed and typewritten portions, ca. 78 p.
- Autographed and typewritten notes, n.d., by David Schwab, Autograph and typewritten notes, 27 p.
  Contains bibliographies of Eliot's works and of critical writings on Eliot
- Periodical Photographs of T.S. Eliot 1926-1933, 4 photographs